DANIEL MEZA

FULL STACK SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

ABOUT ME

My love for software development started back 10 years ago when I took a C# class for fun. Learning new languages and technologies has been a hobby of mine ever since. I thoroughly enjoy finding solutions to complex problems. Extremely lucky to be in a field where I can be a lifelong learner to continue growing and creating new opportunities!

TECH STACK AND SKILLS

JavaScript

Python

React

Django/Django REST

SQL/PostgreSQL/MSSQL

CSS

C#

HTML

GitHub

Git

Java

Bootstrap

Fluent in Spanish

CONTACT ME AT

- Nashville Metropolitan Area
- github.com/danny128373
- dm3f90@gmail.com
- danny128373.github.io/
- in linkedin.com/in/danielmeza1

TECHNICAL EDUCATION

Nashville Software School

Full Stack Software Developer | Apr 2020 - present

- A full-time, accelerated six month program focusing on the development of core understanding and technical competence in both front-end and back-end.
- Primary concentrations include HTML, CSS, JavaScript, React, Python, and Django.
- Implemented full CRUD functionality on my capstone and developed a mobile friendly version of the app named RepCount.
- Gained experience working in teams in a virtual environment creating web applications.
- Developed my final capstone using React for the front-end and Django REST API for the back-end.

Udacity

Application Developer | Oct 2018 - Jan 2020

- Created several android applications using Java and XML.
- Learned about Web APIs and how to use them, and the basics of networking in Android, including HTTP networking, JSON parsing, and threads.

EDUCATION

Nashville Software School

Full Stack Software Developer | Apr 2020 - present

Middle Tennessee State University

BS in Mathematics, GPA 3.5 | 2010 - 2013

- Minor in Education
- 1.5 years of C#

EXPERIENCE

Lead Teller

Wells Fargo | Apr 2016 - present

- Display a friendly, positive attitude toward serving customers and possess strong customer service skills.
- Engage customers in a meaningful financial conversations that include understanding what's important to them, and introduce them to bankers, when appropriate, to further asses their needs.

Mathematics Teacher

Sumner, Smith County Schools | Jan 2014 - Jul 2016

- Collaborate with other Math teachers to efficiently plan to coordinate work to provide students the knowledge they need to succeed, taking special consideration that each student learns differently.
- Assess and track student progress of 120+ students throughout the school year, using these reports to guide future lessons. Effective way to cover any gap in student knowledge. Students showed enormous improvement when lesson plans were planned in this way.

PROJECTS

RepCount

Capstone at Nashville Software School

- Developed using React, Bootstrap, HTML, CSS, and JavaScript. RepCount is an app developed for any gym enthusiast to keep track of their workouts and check their progress. This is a mobile friendly version where users can log by muscle(s), exercise name, weight, and reps. Users will have their logs saved and easy to check their progress by exercise name.
- https://github.com/danny128373/Workout-Tracker

Cleverly

Final Capstone at Nashville Software School

- Developed using React, JavaScript, HTML, CSS, Python, and Django REST. Cleverly is an app developed for users interested in an unbelievably random highlight reel of hilarious comments, mind-blowing pictures, ridiculous stories, memes, ingenious puns, cats, and much more.
- https://github.com/danny128373/Cleverly-Client-side